<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>undergraduate research | Jason Forsyth&#39;s Personal Website</title>
    <link>https://jforsyth.github.io/tags/undergraduate-research/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://jforsyth.github.io/tags/undergraduate-research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>undergraduate research</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2019</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://jforsyth.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>undergraduate research</title>
      <link>https://jforsyth.github.io/tags/undergraduate-research/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wearable Computing for Physical Therapy</title>
      <link>https://jforsyth.github.io/project/physical-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jforsyth.github.io/project/physical-therapy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The project will develop a novel wearable computing system for use in physical therapy and rehabilitation
exercises. Often patients undergoing physical therapy are prescribed a set of stretches and exercises to
strengthen an injured muscle group. While outside of the doctor’s office, the physical therapist cannot
observe if the activities are being performed correctly or if at all. Wearable computing solutions have
been developed that will allow human activities to be recognized. However, current approaches are
limited to specific arm and leg motions and not the broader set of activities that would be required in a
general tool usable by medical practitioners. The project would leverage existing machine learning and
human-computer interaction techniques to develop a custom wearable computing system tailored to
rehabilitation exercises of a particular patient. This system would create positive patient outcomes by
providing feedback to the patient and the physical therapist about the quantity and quality of therapy
activities performed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Publications from this work:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sanarea Ali, “Wearable Computing for Physical Rehabilitation”, at the 2019 ACM Capital Region Celebration of Women in Computing Conference (CAPWIC), March 23rd, 2019 &lt;a href=&#34;https://jforsyth.github.io/post/capwic/&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Funding for the work:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JMU CISE Faculty Development Grant: J. Forsyth (PI), M. Stewart (Co-PI), “A Wearable Computing System to Increase Access to Healthcare and Patient Outcomes in Physical Rehabilitation Exercises”. $2,500.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
