<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Jason Forsyth&#39;s Personal Website</title>
    <link>http://jasonforsyth.net/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://jasonforsyth.net/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2023</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://jasonforsyth.net/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>http://jasonforsyth.net/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wearable Computing for Physical Therapy</title>
      <link>http://jasonforsyth.net/project/physical-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jasonforsyth.net/project/physical-therapy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The project will develop a novel wearable computing system for use in physical therapy and rehabilitation
exercises. Often patients undergoing physical therapy are prescribed a set of stretches and exercises to
strengthen an injured muscle group. While outside of the doctor’s office, the physical therapist cannot
observe if the activities are being performed correctly or if at all. Wearable computing solutions have
been developed that will allow human activities to be recognized. However, current approaches are
limited to specific arm and leg motions and not the broader set of activities that would be required in a
general tool usable by medical practitioners. The project would leverage existing machine learning and
human-computer interaction techniques to develop a custom wearable computing system tailored to
rehabilitation exercises of a particular patient. This system would create positive patient outcomes by
providing feedback to the patient and the physical therapist about the quantity and quality of therapy
activities performed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Publications from this work:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Megan Caulfield, Justin Blevins, Jason Forsyth &amp;ldquo;Tactile Instructions for Wearable Physical Rehabilitation&amp;rdquo;, Poster presentation at the 2023 National Conference on Undergraduate Research (NCUR), Eau Claire WI &lt;a href=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/post/ncur2023/&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Megan Caulfield, Jason Forsyth &amp;ldquo;Student Research Short: Wearable Computing for Physical Rehabilitation&amp;rdquo;, Presented at 2022 ACM Capital Region Celebration of Women in Computing (CAPWIC) (refereed as abstract)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sophia Cronin, Tyler Webster, Jason Forsyth “Student Research Short: Wearable Computing for Physical Rehabilitation”, Presentation at 2021 ACM Capital Region Celebration of Women in Computing (CAPWIC) (refereed as abstract) &lt;a href=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/post/ieee-capwic-2021/&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sanarea Ali, “Wearable Computing for Physical Rehabilitation”, at the 2019 ACM Capital Region Celebration of Women in Computing Conference (CAPWIC), March 23rd, 2019 &lt;a href=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/post/capwic/&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Funding for the work:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JMU CISE Faculty Development Grant: J. Forsyth (PI), H. Kirkvold (Co-PI), &amp;ldquo;Designing Wearable Systems for Movement Correction in Physical Therapy Applications&amp;rdquo;, $3,900. Fall 2021&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4-VA  Grant: J. Forsyth (PI), T. Martin (Co-PI), &amp;ldquo;Designing Wearable Systems for Movement Correction in Physical Therapy Applications&amp;rdquo;, $5,000. Fall 2021&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JMU CISE Mini Grant: J. Forsyth,“Prototyping Wearables for Physical Therapy”. $700. Spring 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JMU CISE Faculty Development Grant: J. Forsyth (PI), M. Stewart (Co-PI), “A Wearable Computing System to Increase Access to Healthcare and Patient Outcomes in Physical Rehabilitation Exercises”. $2,500. Spring 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Education</title>
      <link>http://jasonforsyth.net/project/service-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jasonforsyth.net/project/service-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Because pervasive computing systems deal intimately with human needs and interactions, they must be envisioned and developed by interdisciplinary teams that not only understand the technological challenges, but the human ones as well. Crucial to this design process is ensuring these teams are effective and well-functioning. Specifically, it is important that all participants understand the abilities of team members from other disciplines. In earlier work I examined how prototyping exercises helped clarify project goals and establish a disciplinary rapport within teams. More recently I have studied the motivations of capstone design teams. In particular, we have compared the attitudes and experiences of students working on traditional, single discipline projects, such as design of off-road and race cars, as compared to students working in a more interdisciplinary setting designing a smart greenhouse for a local elementary school and assistive technologies for persons with mental and physical disabilities. Looking at these two populations, we found that students who participated in the more interdisciplinary and service-oriented projects felt more personal satisfaction in their engineering work than their peers on the single discipline projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Publications from this work:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kala Meah, &lt;strong&gt;Jason Forsyth&lt;/strong&gt;, James Moscola, “A Smart Sensor Network for an Automated Urban Greenhouse”, 2019 International Conference on Robotics, Electrical and Signal Progressing Techniques (ICREST), Dhaka, Bangladesh, January 10-12, 2019 &lt;a href=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/publication/icrest/&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jason Forsyth&lt;/strong&gt;, Mark Budnik, Randi Shedlosky, Jeff Will, “Effects of Service-Learning Projects on Capstone Student Motivation”, Proceedings of the American Society of Engineering Education Annual Conference – Multidisciplinary Engineering Division, Salt Lake City, Utah, June 24-27, 2018 &lt;a href=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/publication/asee2018multi/&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jason Forsyth&lt;/strong&gt;, Nicole Hesson, “Benefits and Challenges Transitioning to Community Service Multidisciplinary Capstone Projects”, Proceedings of the American Society of Engineering Education Annual Conference – Multidisciplinary Engineering Division, Columbus, Ohio, June 25-28, 2017 &lt;a href=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/publication/greenhouse/&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Funding for the work:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jason Forsyth&lt;/strong&gt;, Nicole Hesson, “Developing an Automated Greenhouse at Alexander D. Goode Elementary School to Serve as a Living Laboratory for Science Education”, $9,746 over 12 months from the York County Community Foundation. Proposal supports research and capital expenses related to the automated greenhouse capstone project. Awarded 1/1/2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jason Forsyth&lt;/strong&gt;, Nicole Hesson; “Addressing Economic and Educational Disadvantages in York City through Engineering Design Projects”, $17,000 over 12 months from the Office of the President. Proposal supports research investigating the impact of service-based multidisciplinary projects on engineering students, faculty, and community partners. Also, provides material support for capstone projects to develop an automated greenhouse, assistive technologies, and targeted curricula for K-8 students. Awarded: 3/24/2016&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pervasive Computing Prototyping Tools</title>
      <link>http://jasonforsyth.net/project/pervasive-computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jasonforsyth.net/project/pervasive-computing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Interdisciplinary design tools facilitate collaboration between engineering and design practitioners to ensure that pervasive products and services are aesthetically pleasing and technologically feasible. From our research with interdisciplinary teams, we found that a shared vocabulary and understanding of design constraints is critical for effective interdisciplinary collaboration. This requires prototyping tools to be accessible across disciplines but sufficiently powerful to develop a working system. Using our technique of electronic storyboards, design teams can electronically “sketch” how a pervasive system should behave and automatically synthesize behavioral descriptions of that system as source code, textual descriptions, and state charts. Descriptions are generated by analyzing storyboard layout, user-applied annotations, and natural language processing of text in the storyboard. During synthesis the electronic storyboard will query the design team to resolve missing or ambiguous information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The descriptions produced by the electronic storyboard, and the tool queries during synthesis, serve as a reflection point for teams to understand if they have properly described their prototype. Storyboard synthesis is quick, taking less than one minute, and enables teams to focus on what a device “should” do, rather than how it is implemented. In a time constrained environment, rapid prototyping tools like electronic storyboards can facilitate better design outcomes by evaluating more prototypes over time. Initial results show this tool is usable by interdisciplinary teams, helps teams evaluate their design, and aids participants in understanding computational properties of the storyboarded systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Publications from this work:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jason Forsyth, Tom Martin, “Extracting Behavioral Information from Electronic Storyboards”, Proceedings of the 6th ACM SIGCHI Symposium on Engineering Interactive Computer Systems, Rome, Italy, June 17-20, 2014 (18% acceptance rate) &lt;a href=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/publication/eics/&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jason Forsyth, Tom Martin, “Tools for Interdisciplinary Design of Pervasive Computing”,International Journal of Pervasive Computing and Communications, vol. 8, no. 2, pp. 112-132, June 2012 (Invited Survey) &lt;a href=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/publication/ipjcc/&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jason Forsyth, “Using Electronic Storyboards to Support Interdisciplinary Design of Pervasive Computing Systems”, Poster Presentation for the Sixth Annual Ph.D. Forum on Pervasive Computing and Communications (PerCom), San Diego, March 20th, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ed Dorsa, Eloise Coupey, Tom Martin, Lisa McNair, Jason Forsyth, Sophie Kim, “Design Thinking Meets Computational Thinking – An Interdisciplinary Exercise in Developing Smart Product”, Industrial Design Society of America Education Symposium, August 2012 &lt;a href=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/publication/idsa&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Funding for the work:&lt;/strong&gt;
Tom Martin (PI), Jason Forsyth, Christian James, “Storycoding I-Corps Team”, National Science Foundation. Award Date: 4/1/2015. Amount: $50,000. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nsf.gov/awardsearch/showAward?AWD_ID=1535818&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wearable Safety Systems</title>
      <link>http://jasonforsyth.net/project/wearable-safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jasonforsyth.net/project/wearable-safety/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wearable safety devices provide continuous monitoring and sensing to protect human life. Safety-critical pervasive systems are challenging to develop as these systems must be easy to use while providing the user with reliable and timely warnings. Examining the hazards faced by construction workers, many are at risk of carbon monoxide poisoning when working with gasoline powered tools in or around enclosed spaces. To address this problem, we integrated a pulse oximetry sensor into the headband of a typical construction helmet to non-invasively measure blood gas concentrations. Based upon our reliability analysis the integrated sensor can warn the worker of impending carbon monoxide poisoning with 99% reliability. This work was the first to address reliability of wearable pulse oximetry during motion and has been recognized by IEEE Transactions on Automation Science and Engineering as the best paper of 2012. Building on this work, we have developed a warning system for road-side workers and emergency personnel to estimate potential vehicle strikes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Publications from this work:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jason Forsyth, Tom Martin, Deborah Young-Corbett, Ed Dorsa, “Feasibility of Intelligent Monitoring of Construction Workers for Carbon Monoxide Poisoning”, IEEE Trans. on Automation Science and Engineering, Volume 9, Issue 3, pp. 505-515, July 2012 (16% acceptance rate) (2012 Best Paper Award) &lt;a href=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/publication/tase-journal/&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;J. Forsyth, T.L. Martin, D. Young-Corbett, E. Dorsa; “Feasibility Study of a Wearable Carbon Monoxide Warning System for Construction Workers,” 2011 IEEE International Conference on Pervasive Computing and Communications (PerCom),  Seattle, WA, March 21-25 2011, pp.28-36 (11% of 156 accepted as long papers) &lt;a href=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/publication/percom/&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jason Forsyth, Tom Martin, Darrell Bowman, “Feasibility of GPS-based Warning System for Roadside Workers”, International Conference on Connected Vehicles and Expo, November 3-7, 2014, Vienna, Austria (33% acceptance rate). &lt;a href=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/publication/iccv/&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
