<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Undergraduate Research | Jason Forsyth&#39;s Personal Website</title>
    <link>http://jasonforsyth.net/categories/undergraduate-research/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://jasonforsyth.net/categories/undergraduate-research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Undergraduate Research</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2024</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://jasonforsyth.net/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Undergraduate Research</title>
      <link>http://jasonforsyth.net/categories/undergraduate-research/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Papers at SIEDS 2023 and ICAT Day Panelist</title>
      <link>http://jasonforsyth.net/post/sieds2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jasonforsyth.net/post/sieds2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Student Research at SIES 2023&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The work of several JMU honors students and capstone projects was presented last week at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://engineering.virginia.edu/ieee-sieds&#34;&gt;2023 IEEE Systems and Information Engineering Design Symposium (SIEDS)&lt;/a&gt; hosted by the University of Virginia. Sanda Thura (JMU Computer Science &#39;23) presented his honors thesis on applications of machine learning for cardiac disease detection on embedded systems. His paper can be viewed &lt;a href=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/pdf/thursa-sieds-2023.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Sanda was advised by myself, Dr. Kevin Molloy (JMU CS), and Dr. Jacob Couch (Johns Hopkins Applied Physics Lab).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JMU Engineering capstone students (Ritavash Chowdhury, Michael Chung, and Dylan Gnagey) presented their senior project on automated systems to detect correct posture during a bench press exercises. Their paper is available &lt;a href=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/pdf/chowdhury-sieds-2023.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table width=&#34;99%&#34;&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href = &#34;/img/sanda-sieds.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/img/sanda-sieds.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; &gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href = &#34;/img/gym-sense-sieds.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/img/gym-sense-sieds.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; &gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was my personal pleasure to be the General Chair for SIEDS 2023. I look forward to continuing into 2024 and extending JMU&#39;s engagement with the conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table width=&#34;99%&#34;&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href = &#34;/img/sieds-jmu.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/img/sieds-jmu.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; &gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ICAT Day Panelist&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a pleasure to return home to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://icat.vt.edu/&#34;&gt;Virginia Tech Institute for Creativity Arts and Technology (ICAT)&lt;/a&gt; to speak with current graduate students, explore new projects, and catch up with old friends. It is amazing to think that nearly 8 years have elapsed since my time there, so much of which is fundamental to my growth and identity as a faculty member. I am very appreciative of the opportunities ICAT has provided me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table width=&#34;99%&#34;&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href = &#34;/img/icat-panel.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/img/icat-panel.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=900&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href = &#34;/img/icat-speaker.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/img/icat-speaker.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=900&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Students Present Wearables Research at NCUR 2023</title>
      <link>http://jasonforsyth.net/post/ncur2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jasonforsyth.net/post/ncur2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Megan Caulfield (JMU Engineering &#39;24) and Justin Blevins (JMU Engineering &#39;23) presented their research on wearable computing systems and haptic feedback. Their work explores how to provide haptic &amp;quot;instructions&amp;quot; to guide a person&#39;s motion.
This work is an initial step on our larger progress to create general systems to provide feedback during &lt;a href=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/project/physical-therapy/&#34;&gt;physical therapy&lt;/a&gt;. Their poster is available &lt;a href=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/pdf/ncur-poster-2023.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Justin will be graduating this semester and beginning work with Northrup Grumman in Charlottesville. Megan is a rising senior and will continue her research as honors thesis by exploring haptic feedback to improve braille reading and writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table width=&#34;99%&#34;&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href = &#34;/img/ncur1.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/img/ncur1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; &gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href = &#34;/img/ncur2.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/img/ncur2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; &gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASEE and FIE Papers. Additional 4VA Grants Awarded.</title>
      <link>http://jasonforsyth.net/post/fall2022-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jasonforsyth.net/post/fall2022-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;4va-grant-with-sol-lim-virginia-tech&#34;&gt;4-VA Grant with Sol Lim (Virginia Tech)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sol Lim, Michael Stewart (JMU), I have received a 4VA grant to explore wearable haptic systems for persons with visual impairement entitled: &amp;quot;Supporting College Students with Impaired Vision in a Shared Housing Through Haptic-Guided Peripersonal Navigation&amp;quot;
The work will be led by Dr. Lim and her students with supporting hardware and software development from JMU.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;asee-paper-on-convergent-problems-and-entrepreneurial-learning&#34;&gt;ASEE Paper On Convergent Problems and Entrepreneurial Learning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stu Thompson (Bucknell), Alan Cheville (Bucknell) and I have published a paper at ASEE examining how the Entrepreneurially-Minded Learning (EML) framework can be applied to convergent problems. The work outlines a definition for convergent problems and how the EML framework and its associated KEEN Cards might be used to provide instructional activities for faculty. The paper was presented at the 2022 ASEE National Conference in the ENT Division.
The paper is available &lt;a href=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/pdf/asee-2022-eml-convergence.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fie-paper-on-engineering-perceptions&#34;&gt;FIE Paper on Engineering Perceptions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A multi-discplinary team involving Virginia Tech (Homero Murzi, Karen Soto, Matthew James, and Lisa Schibelius), Virginia (Diana Duran), and JMU (Jason Forsyth) has explored how artistic methods can be utilized to understand student perceptions of engineering. First-year students were asked at the beginning and end of their engineering experience to draw a response to the prompt, &amp;quot;What is Engineering?&amp;quot;.
Analyzing those results differences between institutions and perceptions have been identified. The paper was presented as a Work-In-Progress at the 2022 Frontier of Education conference and is available &lt;a href=&#34;pdf/drawing-fie-2022.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Research Students. Additional Grants Awarded.</title>
      <link>http://jasonforsyth.net/post/fall2021-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jasonforsyth.net/post/fall2021-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are many new items to report for the Wearable Computer Research group this fall semester!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;new-undergraduate-researchers&#34;&gt;New Undergraduate Researchers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the graduation of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/sophiacronin/&#34;&gt;Sophia Cronin&lt;/a&gt; (Microsoft) and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/lijonathancj/&#34;&gt;Jonathan Li&lt;/a&gt; (Dev Technology Group) we are in need of new undergraduate researchers. We are excited to have join the research group:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Megan Caulfield (JMU Engineering &#39;24)&lt;/strong&gt;: will continue development of wearable and electronic textile solutions to provide feedback during movement correction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dawson Dolanksy (JMU Computer Science &#39;23)&lt;/strong&gt;: will focus on extending our real-time management and streaming for inertial measurement units to provide high-quality data during activity recognition and feedback.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Riley White (JMU Computer Science &#39;23)&lt;/strong&gt;: brings new capabilities in machine learning to the research group. As an already &lt;a href=&#34;https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/abstract/document/9680230?casa_token=DqZlsWAyBXIAAAAA:fEKznJXNyfBWqUQZv_vogGktv3e5U57LPkt3NCuuVUOwrx3h33EB1fJ_gUVB7OQ3BlRO4FUiMw&#34;&gt;peer-reviewed author&lt;/a&gt; he will develop new methods for skill estimation during physical therapy exercises.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;table width=&#34;99%&#34;&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/img/megan.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Megan Caulfield&#34; width=&#34;250&#34;&gt; Megan Caulfield&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/img/dawson.png&#34; alt=&#34;Dawson Dolanksy&#34; width=&#34;210&#34;&gt;Dawson Dolanksy&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/img/riley.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Riley White&#34; width=&#34;188&#34;&gt;Riley White&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;new-grants-awarded&#34;&gt;New Grants Awarded&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two new grants have been awarded to support our work in &lt;a href=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/project/physical-therapy/&#34;&gt;physical therapy rehabilitation&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;An external 4-VA grant &amp;quot;&lt;em&gt;Designing Wearable Systems for Movement Correction in Physical Therapy Applications&lt;/em&gt;&amp;quot; was awarded between JMU and Virginia Tech (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.faculty.ece.vt.edu/tlmartin/&#34;&gt;Dr. Tom Martin&lt;/a&gt; Co-PI) to support prototyping efforts and travel to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://icat.vt.edu/studios.html&#34;&gt;ICAT studios&lt;/a&gt; to capture high-resolution motion capture data. A short abstract is &lt;a href=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/pdf/Forsyth-4VA-Short-Abstract.pdf&#34;&gt;available&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;An internal JMU CISE grant was awarded with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jmu.edu/cise/engineering/people/all-people/kirkvold-heather.shtml&#34;&gt;Dr. Heather Kirkvold&lt;/a&gt; (Co-PI) to enable textiles prototyping in the new JMU Engineering Textiles studio with undergraduate researchers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, the group continues to build out its technical capabilities to prototype wearable recognition and feedback systems for physical exercises. With these new additions and funding mechanisms we expect continued growth in productivity and opportunities for our undergraduate researchers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Promotion to Associate Professor of Engineering</title>
      <link>http://jasonforsyth.net/post/promotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jasonforsyth.net/post/promotion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Based upon action by the JMU Board of Visitors on April 16th I have been promoted to Associate Professor of Engineering effective August 25th, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I greatly appreciate the guidance and support from my JMU Engineering colleagues over the last three years. Furthermore, a great debt is owed to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jasonforsyth.net/categories/undergraduate-research/&#34;&gt;undergraduate researchers&lt;/a&gt; in the Wearable Computing Lab for this milestone. I thank you all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/img/office-door.png&#34; alt=&#34;At least the door change is effective immediately.&#34; title=&#34;At least the door change is effective immediately.&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;At least the door change is effective immediately.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wearable Computing Lab Researchers Present at Several Conferences</title>
      <link>http://jasonforsyth.net/post/ieee-capwic-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jasonforsyth.net/post/ieee-capwic-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Despite the pandemic, Spring 2021 has been a productive time for the undergraduate researchers in the Wearable Computing Lab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/img/stephen-ieee-conf.png&#34; alt=&#34;Stephen Mitchell presents his work at IEEE SouthEast Conference&#34; title=&#34;Stephen Mitchell presents his work at IEEE SouthEast Conference&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Stephen Mitchell presents his work at IEEE SouthEast Conference&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stephen Mitchell has presented his latest work at IEEE SouthEast Conference. This &lt;a href=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/pdf/MitchellS-T7S2-ieee-ready.pdf&#34;&gt;short paper&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/pdf/Mitchell-IEEE-Presentation.pdf&#34;&gt;presentation&lt;/a&gt; is an extension of his previous work that was presented at &lt;a href=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/post/marcus2019&#34;&gt;MARCUS 2019&lt;/a&gt;. Additional analysis is on-going and has been accepted as publication for a &lt;a href=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/pdf/mitchell-sieds-camera-ready.pdf&#34;&gt;full paper&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&#34;https://engineering.virginia.edu/departments/engineering-systems-and-environment/academics/ieee-sieds&#34;&gt;SIEDS 2021&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/img/sophia-tyler-capwic.png&#34; alt=&#34;Sophia Cronin and Tyler Webster present at ACM CAPWIC 2021&#34; title=&#34;Sophia Cronin and Tyler Webster present at ACM CAPWIC 2021&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Sophia Cronin and Tyler Webster present at ACM CAPWIC 2021&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sophia Cronin and Tyler Webster also presented their work on wearable haptic and visual feedback systems for physical therapy rehabilitation at the ACM Capital Region Celebration of Women in Computing (CAPWIC). Their &lt;a href=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/pdf/capwic-2021-abstract.pdf&#34;&gt;abstract&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/pdf/cronin-webster-capwic-2021-presentation.pdf&#34;&gt;presentation&lt;/a&gt; are available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jonathan Li (Computer Science) completed his one year project developing machine learning tools to manage our human activity recognition data. His work finalizes our data pipeline to capture activity data, clean/label/manage the information, and evaluate novel HAR approaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both of these works are supported by JMU CISE Faculty Development and Mini Grants.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Undergraduate Researcher Presents at MARCUS 2019</title>
      <link>http://jasonforsyth.net/post/marcus2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jasonforsyth.net/post/marcus2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/img/stephen-mitchell-marcus.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Stephen Mitchell at MARCUS 2019&#34;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sophomore JMU Engineering student and undergraduate researcher in the Wearable Computing Group, Stephen Mitchell, presented his initial research on measuring athlete performance at the 2019 Mid-Atlantic Regional Conference on Undergraduate Scholarship (MARCUS) at Randolph College. His work examines using low-cost inertial measurement units (IMU) to calculate an athletic performance measure called the &amp;quot;Drop Jump Ratio&amp;quot;. These IMUs are low-cost, light weight, and more mobile than traditional force plates used to calculate the drop jump ratio.
More information can be found in his &lt;a href=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/pdf/mitchell-marcus-abstract.pdf&#34;&gt;abstract&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/pdf/mitchell-marcus-poster.pdf&#34;&gt;poster&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stephen&#39;s work is supported through collaborations with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bucknell.edu/fac-staff/stu-thompson&#34;&gt;Dr. Stu Thompson&lt;/a&gt; in the Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering at Bucknell University and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jmu.edu/biology/people/current-people/faculty/faculty-wunderlich.shtml&#34;&gt;Dr. Rosha Wunderlich&lt;/a&gt; in the Department of Biology at JMU.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Undergraduate Researcher Presents at ACM CAPWIC</title>
      <link>http://jasonforsyth.net/post/capwic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jasonforsyth.net/post/capwic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/img/sanarea-ali-capwic.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sanarea Ali at CAPWIC 2019&#34; title=&#34;Sanarea Ali at CAPWIC 2019&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Sanarea Ali at CAPWIC 2019&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JMU Engineering student, Sanarea Ali, gave a flash talk on her proposed wearable computing system for physical rehabilitation at the ACM Capital Region Celebration of Women in Computing (CAPWIC). Her research examines how wearable computing can support clinicians in understanding patient injuries and improving their recovery. The abstract of her talk is included &lt;a href=&#34;http://jasonforsyth.net/pdf/Abstract-Wearable-Computing-for-Physical-Rehabilitation.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
